As you saw in the last video,
正如你在上个视频中所看到的
trying to handle every kind of scenario when
在处理意外的输入时
dealing with unexpected input can be a bit much.
尝试处理每种情形会比较麻烦
There's actually a much simpler way of dealing with this in Python.
实际上在 Python 中有一种简单得多的处理方式
Here, you learn how to handle errors with try and except blocks.
下面你将学习如何使用 try 和 except 块处理错误
First, let's learn more about what errors in Python are.
首先 我们将详细了解 Python 中有哪些错误
We've seen error messages due to several reasons in this course,
我们已经在这门课程中看到因为多个原因而出现的错误消息
and we can separate them into two types,
可以将这些错误分为两大类
syntax errors and exceptions.
语法错误和异常
Syntax errors occur when Python can't interpret
当我们没有遵守正确的 Python 语法规则
our code since we didn't follow the correct syntax for Python.
导致 Python 无法解析代码时 就会出现语法错误
These are errors you're likely to get when you make a typo,
当你出现拼写错误或一开始学习 Python 时
or you're first starting to learn Python.
就有可能遇到这种错误
Here, I get a syntax error because I
在此示例中 我遇到了语法错误
missed the ending quotation mark at the end of the string.
因为我在该字符串的末尾丢失了右引号
I can see this in the error message,
可以从错误消息中看出这一点
SyntaxError: End of line when scanning string literal.
SyntaxError: EOL while scanning string literal
The other kind of error,
另一种错误是异常
exceptions occur when unexpected things happen during the execution of the code.
在执行代码的过程中 可能会发生意外情况 这时候就会出现异常
Here, although our code is syntactically correct,
在此示例中 虽然我们的代码没有语法错误
we run into an exception because a string spelling out
但是我们遇到了异常
10 isn't a valid argument for the int function.
因为拼写为 10 的字符串并不是 int 函数的有效参数
There are different types of built-in exceptions in Python,
Python 中有不同类型的内置异常
and you can see which exception is being thrown here in the error message.
你可以在这里的错误消息中查看抛出了哪个异常
Value error is one type of exception.
valueError 是一种异常类型
It occurs when a built-in operation or function is
如果向内置操作或函数提供类型正确但是值不合适的参数
given an argument with the correct type but an inappropriate value.
就会发生这种异常
Here's another example that there was an exception.
这是另一个抛出异常的示例
Here, we try to reference a variable name that we didn't define yet.
我们尝试引用一个尚未定义的变量名
So, we get a name error exception.
因此出现了 nameError 异常
Again, this code is syntactically correct,
这段代码同样没有语法错误
but when Python gets to this line of code,
但是当 Python 执行到这行代码时
it can't find the value for this variable when it tries to run it.
无法找到这个变量的值
So, it raises an exception and stops the code.
因此抛出异常并停止运行代码